# Jan Jongboom

### Firefox OS Contributor at Telenor Digital

janjongboom@gmail.com

## Summary

Hi! Are you a recruiter for an agency? In that case please do not send any InMails.

I'm trying to make the world a better place by bringing internet to the 4.5 billion people that do not have access to it.

Software enthusiast since the age of 10, with around 8 years of professional experience. Language agnostic, but currently spending the majority of my time in javascript. At the moment I'm working as Firefox OS contributor and evangelist for Telenor Digital. In the past eight years I have worked on software for SMEs; on the largest .NET website in the Netherlands; on the first online collaborative IDE; and on the only truly open mobile OS. In companies ranging from a four-man shop, to a VC backed startup, and a 40,000 people enterprise.

Besides development I like to spend a big portion of my time on community building, I've spoken at a variety of conferences, a.o. JSCamp.asia, O'Reilly VelocityConf EU, Yandex' YAC (see http://lanyrd.com/profile/drbernhard/); but also local community building in Telenor markets through meetups, app days, training, etc.

Some other stuff I've done: cheating library for Football Manager (> 500,000 downloads); had Scott Guthrie show off my work on stage (cross platform Azure tooling); answered a ton of questions on Stack Overflow; made javascript weekly three times; wrote for .NET magazine; built highly popular AngularJS/Firefox OS/offline boilerplate. And I contributed to Cloud9 IDE, Gaia, Gecko, substance.io, request, async, Ace editor, architect, and a ton of other projects.

# Experience

### Firefox OS Contributor at Telenor Digital

January 2013 - Present (1 year 8 months)

Running two jobs, first as a Mozilla Firefox OS contributor. I'm part of the keyboard team and write code / review for both gaia and gecko, I did a fair share of the gecko work for 3rd party keyboards. Before becoming a keyboard peer I've been all over the place, touched a ton of other modules. I'm making smooth interfaces on very cheap hardware (f.e. the 25\$ smartphone).

Second part is evangelism, help with community building in markets where Telenor wants to launch Firefox OS devices, ranging from app days to private training sessions to presentations. Eastern Europe and South-East Asia mostly.

I also sit in planes a lot.

### Javascript developer at Cloud9 IDE

October 2011 - January 2013 (1 year 4 months)

Developer at the Amsterdam / San Francisco based startup Cloud9 IDE. We were building an online IDE that offered realtime collaboration, virtual machines in the cloud and built in cloud deployments on top of general IDE features (static analysis, debugging, refactoring). I joined the company approximately two months after they raised Series A and left when we ran out of money, so I've had my fair share of startup experience.

I've basically been all over the place, from debugging to billing to editor features.

2 recommendations available upon request

#### .NET Developer at Funda

December 2008 - October 2011 (2 years 11 months)

Funda is the leading real estate portal in the Netherlands, serving around 250.000.000 page views to 4 mio unique visitors each month. I've touched basically every part of the code in the three years that I've been working here.

Special bonus project: Smart searchbox, extremely fast and intelligent autocomplete box. Primary interface for searching locations; contains 200.000 entries, and understands hierarchy, spelling errors, etc. Handles 300 query's per second at an average response time of 5 ms. See my blog under the section 'Algorithms'.

2 recommendations available upon request

#### Self-employed at Young3

January 2008 - January 2009 (1 year 1 month)

Tried to create software that could do sentiment analysis based on news items, blogs and forums (these were the pre-twitter times!) To fund these experiments I did freelance work for SME's, mainly software to keep administration and websites in sync automatically, and a couple of integrations of the ITSD CMS.

#### ASP.NET / WPF Developer at Arlanet

March 2008 - December 2008 (10 months)

Arlanet is a software development company doing both project work for SME's, and developing several own products based on ASP.NET and WPF.

Most of my time I spent on the in-house developed hosted applications. Furthermore custom built software, workflow apps, etc. Also Office plugins in VSTO, and reporting service supported tools.

#### ASP.NET Developer at ITSD B.V.

January 2006 - February 2008 (2 years 2 months)

ITSD is a consultancy company that had a web application development from 2006 to 2008. We targeted SME's, providing them with both websites built on our own CMS, and creating applications to automate their business. The largest project we ran was a callcenter application for > 100 concurrent agents. I was part of a three men technical team.

The development department was sold to Ouwehand Design after my resignation. I continued doing freelance work for them.

Written recommendation from the owner available.

# Skills & Expertise

JavaScript
Software Development
.NET
ASP.NET
Cloud Computing
REST
Architectures
Integration
WPF
CMS

## **Projects**

**Start-ups** 

### **Cloud9 IDE and MS Azure integration**

October 2011 to Present

**Enterprise Software** 

Members: Jan Jongboom, Jos Uijterwaal, Erin Lockhart, Matt Pardee, Glenn Block

Cloud9's integration with MS Azure enables developers to deploy applications to Microsoft's Azure Cloud solution. Currently it's the only way to deploy an application to the Cloud from non-Microsoft platforms.

## Certifications

#### MCPD .NET 3.5

Microsoft

### Education

#### **University of Amsterdam**

Information Science, 2007 - 2008

### St. Michael College

Atheneum

# Interests

politics, art, socializing, after-work-drinks

# Jan Jongboom

Firefox OS Contributor at Telenor Digital

janjongboom@gmail.com



# 4 people have recommended Jan

"It is often said that some programmers are a hundred times more productive than others. Jan is an example of this group. When he puts his mind to something, he gets things done at an enormous pace. He may grumble sometimes, but he gets the job done and gets it done well. Not only is Jan an outstanding developer, he also has a great sense of humor and is a very vivid presenter."

— **Zef Hemel**, VP of Engineering, Cloud9 IDE, managed Jan at Cloud9 IDE, Inc.

"Jan and I worked together to support in Cloud 9 for publishing node.js applications to Windows Azure. Timelines were short, this was a high profile project, and he came to the table with no real background in Azure. I was amazed at how fast Jan was able to grasp the core Azure architecture / REST APIs and get the functionality implemented. He turned around the project very quickly. The result was a one-click experience that makes it really easy to deploy! I would definitely work with Jan again in the future."

— Glenn Block, Senior Program Manager - Windows Azure SDK for Node.js, Microsoft, was with another company when working with Jan at Cloud9 IDE, Inc

"The one thing I like most about working in software development is the people. Good developers are often a bit unconventional, think out of the box and are always smart. Jan ticks all of the boxes and was a pleasure to work with. Jan is not a great fan of discipline and regulations, but when he's on track, he is incredibly productive and usually designed solutions that exceeded my expectations."

— Teun Duynstee, Head of development and architecture, Funda, managed Jan at Funda

"Jan is the youngest, yet one of the most senior developers at Funda. A likable guy, always in for fun, self confident and aware of his high potential. Jan is very serious about his work though. I have seen him creating smart solutions fast during the time I worked for Funda. He is always on top of new trends and innovations regarding software development, skilled at them by the time most people first hear of them. Jan's curiosity and ability to adopt new skills stretch beyond software development. He is an all round creative thinker and shares his ideas with great enthusiasm."

— Henk Kok, IT Consultant, Funda, was with another company when working with Jan at Funda

Contact Jan on LinkedIn